# KUNO WOUDT CURRICULUM VITAE

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

name Jacobus Louis Woudt URL frob.nl

email kuno@frob.nl

<u>DOB</u> 1976 / 07 / 23 phone +593 99 4050 815 <u>POB</u> Leeuwarden, NL

+31 651 255 985

nationality Dutch

#### **SKILLS**

I am a generalist, full-stack web developer skilled in **JavaScript**, **Python**, **PHP** and **PerI**. When writing client-side javascript I prefer using modern technologies like **web components** or Facebook's **React.js**, though have many years of experience using **jQuery** and plain JavaScript. Server-side I have a good knowledge of python WSGI frameworks such as **webob** and **werkzeug/flask**. For dealing with data I have a thorough knowledge of **SQL**, but also enjoy working with NoSQL databases such as **Redis** and **CouchDB** or extracting data from **XML** using **XSLT/XPath**.

I prefer an environment where automated tests, continuous deployment and distributed version control are used for most projects.

In my spare time I am experimenting with Semantic Web technologies (Linked Data, RDF) and learning functional programming with Haskell.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### January 2014 — present / Follow Up Boss

Position held: Developer

Follow Up Boss is a lead management application for real estate agents.

## August 2013 — January 2014 / Zest Software

Zest Software develops informational websites, intranets and web applications for knowledge-intensive organizations.

As a developer for Zest Software I am one of two developers working on small websites built with Django, and large content management applications built with Plone.

#### February 2010 — July 2013 / MetaBrainz

Position held: Developer

MusicBrainz is a community-maintained open source encyclopedia of music information. It consists of a website and webservice written in perl, and a fair amount of javascript on some of the data entry screens. The main site uses PostgreSQL as the back-end database and a lucene based search server written in java.

As a contractor for MetaBrainz I was part of a team of three paid developers and a large community of volunteers. I started during a time when we were doing a full rewrite of the musicbrainz.org server software, which went live on May 2011. In the following two years I've mostly worked on the musicbrainz.org server software, working with our community of users and clients to fix bugs as they get reported and add features.

As part of a small team of developers with no system administrators, I was also responsible for maintaining various bits of infrastructure, most importantly nagios monitoring of our servers.

### May 2006 — January 2010 / COPE

Position held: Developer and System Administrator

COPE aims to provide insight into corporate data. To this end, COPE has developed a generic online survey tool and a tool for 360 degree feedback assessments. My role at COPE was to develop new features for these two products, both generic enhancements of the software and custom features for specific clients. I was the maintainer of the survey tool codebase. Technologies used are mainly PHP and MySQL, with XML/XSLT to seperate logic from presentation, both on screen (HTML/CSS) and on paper (PDF, Prince XML).

In addition to being a developer, I was also a network and system administrator for a number of machines in a growing network of physical and virtual machines, both colocated production servers and development servers at our office. These mainly run Debian GNU/Linux, with apache, php, mysgl, and other services.

### **INTERNSHIPS**

# February 2004 - June 2004 / Computer Vision Laboratory, Noordelijke Hogeschool Leeuwarden Graduation project

Research and implementation of realtime motion detection and estimation for video games. Various game prototypes and a final game were developed using C# and Managed DirectX 9. The motion detection algorithms were implemented in C++, as part of an in-house vision library.

# September 2001 - January 2002 / Compiler Technology, Philips Research Laboratories Eindhoven internship

Add support for Very Long Instruction Word CPUs to a generic cpu emulator written in Java. The goal of this project was to add support support for a NXP/Philips TriMedia CPU, while keeping the code general enough so other VLIW CPUs can be added later.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Sep 1999 - Jul 2004 / Noordelijke Hogeschool Leeuwarden

Bachelor of Engineering, Informatica (Computer Science)

# Aug 1997 - Jul 1998 / Hogeschool Enschede

Computertechniek (no degree)

#### Aug 1992 - Jul 1997 / MBO College De Friese Poort, Sneek

Diploma Elektronica/Telematica (senior secondary vocational education, degree in electronics/telematics)

### LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

- Native language: Frisian
- · Fluent in English and Dutch